# ANURAG TRIPATHI

GitHub ♦ Google Scholar ♦ LinkedIn Homepage ♦ Medium Blog Email- nowitsanurag@gmail.com

A graduate in Electronics & Communication Engineering with over one year of experience in IT Risk Management and Artificial Intelligence. Proficient with Python and its web frameworks as well as Machine Learning and Deep Learning.

#### **EDUCATION**

Amity University

Bachelor of Technology

2017 - 2021

Noida, India

- · Department: Electronics and Communication Engineering
- Relevant courses: Artificial Intelligence (CSE401), Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning (ECE325), Neural Networks and Deep Learning (ECE326), Introduction to Cloud Computing (IT423), IoT Based System Design (ECE435), Digital Image Processing (ECE404)
- · Thesis: Classification of Cervical cancer using Machine learning and Deep learning (Report)
- · Advisor: Ms. Anupama Bhan
- · GPA: 7.84/10 (First Division)

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Com OlhoFeb 2022-Oct 2022Product ManagerGurgaon, India

- Developed web application back end components with **Django** while communicating with clients to identify their needs/goals and work on meeting them.
- · Obtained adequate experience in reviewing **Python** code for running the troubleshooting test-cases and bug issues.
- · Experienced with front-end technologies, such as **HTML**, **CSS** for good UI development.
- · Worked on the improvement of data protection and security by implementing face login using **deep learning** on company's platform.
- · Database knowledge and python interaction with databases.
- · Experienced with **selenium** web-based automation tools and developing under **Linux** environment.
- · Designed and developed analysis systems to extract information from large scale data.
- · (LOR)

## **Ennoventure Technologies Pvt. Ltd**

Software Engineer

Aug 2021- Feb 2022 Bangalore, India

- · Experienced with **flask** framework.
- · Responsible for creating and testing APIs and deploying in **Azure cloud**.
- · Updated and optimized 20+ stored procedures using MySQL.
- · Developed SQL stored procedure, functions and style sheets to reduce data retrieval time by 50%.
- · Re-structured schemas with 50+ tables to enhance data integrity.
- · Responsible for training **machine learning** models on the company's patented product for identification when scanned from mobile app.
- · Optimized classification algorithms for applications (vyu app on Google Play Store).

#### **INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE**

Com Olho Feb 2021-June 2021

Research Intern- Data Science

Gurgaon, India

- · Use of high speed **computer vision** to study the effect of vehicular frequency over time to pollution.
- · Implemented vehicle detection at national highway 8 (Gurgaon, India) using OpenCV model.
- · Model was running for 1 month to get the trend of frequency and density of vehicles observed with respect to real time air quality index.
- · Study revealed that 75% of city pollution is contributed by vehicular density.
- · (Certificate)

ClearExamDec 2020-Feb 2021Software DeveloperDelhi, India

- · Extracted and collected data to create needed reports.
- · Design and maintain **SQL** scripts.
- · Validated accuracy of data to ensure database integrity.
- · Created and optimized diverse SQL queries.
- · Generate reports and spreadsheets detailing database changes and performance.
- · (Certificate), (LOR)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Anurag Tripathi, A. Arora and A. Bhan, "Classification of Cervical Cancer Detection using Machine Learning Algorithms," 2021 6th International Conference on Inventive Computation Technologies (ICICT), 2021, pp. 827-835, doi: 10.1109/ICICT50816.2021.9358570.
- Anurag Tripathi, A. Arora and A. Bhan, "Classification of cervical cancer using Deep Learning Algorithm," 2021
   5th International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Control Systems (ICICCS), 2021, pp. 1210-1218, doi: 10.1109/ICICCS51141.2021.9432382.
- Reza, M. et al. (2021). Automatic Diabetes and Liver Disease Diagnosis and Prediction through SVM and KNN Algorithms.
   In: Anurag Tripathi, Hassanien, A.E., Bhattacharyya, S. (eds) Emerging Technologies in Data Mining and Information Security. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, vol 1300. Springer, Singapore., doi: 10.1007/978-981-33-4367-2 56.
- Implementation of Machine Learning using Python for Classification of Human Limb Movement using UWB antenna.
   Classified human limb movement using machine learning with python by fabricating on body ultra-wide band antennas which were used on the human limb to record readings for limb movements. (communicated to JMLR)

#### **PROJECTS**

- **Design and fabrication of compact Ultra-Wide Band antenna**. Designed and simulated a compact Ultra-Wideband antenna (29.5 mm x 30 mm) on CST software. Fabricated antenna on PCB; tested in an anechoic chamber. Plotted antennae parameters (S-parameter, polarization, power radiation etc.) from readings obtained deploying a Vector Network Analyzer
- Face-X —Recognition of faces by different algorithms and frameworks. Despite a variety of open-source face recognition frameworks available, there was no ready-made solution to implement. In this project all kinds of algorithms are implemented and even with various operations that can be implemented in a frontal face. The available algorithms processed only high-resolution static shots and performed sufficiently well. (GitHub)
- Face mask detection using YOLO Algorithm Detection of face mask using YOLO Algorithm. (Blog), (Project Link)
- · To display deep learning model on Pima Indians onset of diabetes binary classification problem. (Report)
- · Developing a CNN for MNIST handwritten digit classification. (Report), (PPT)

#### **ORGANIZATIONAL WORK**

· Coordinating Committee, Celebration of Belongingness. (Certificate)	April - May 2020
· Coordinating Committee, 7 <sup>th</sup> IEEE SPIN.	March 2020
· Volunteering Committee, 6 <sup>th</sup> IEEE SPIN. (Certificate)	March 2019
· Volunteering Committee, 5 <sup>th</sup> IEEE SPIN. (Certificate)	Feb 2018

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR & SERVICES**

JAX Foundation Oct 2020
NGO Volunteering Noida, India

- · Worked on the topic of Cancer Awareness.
- · Working with community program leaders and advocates to make resources available to those in need.
- · Taught unprivileged kids every weekend and introduced them to computers and the internet world.
- · (Certificate), (Report)

Study Abroad ProgramNov-Dec 2019Student Exchange ProgramLondon, UK

- Attended lectures at Birkbeck, University of London, and Amity University, London for 5 weeks in the 5th semester.
- Opted elective Courses: Global Information Technology (CSIT219) and Understanding Principles & Practices of Commercial Research (IB206)
- In due course also visited Oxford University, Cambridge University, Northampton University, and Brunel University London for attending guest lectures.
- · (Certificate)

Lakshy FoundationApril-Sept 2019NGO VolunteeringUttar Pradesh, India

- · Worked in healthcare and assisted the fundraising team with writing grant proposals.
- Developed and created programs and monitored effectiveness towards individual participants in community workshops to promote various programs and educate the public about needs.
- · Helped to develop an online platform for stray animal adoption.
- · (Experience Letter)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

· Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with <b>Python</b> ), Michigan University. (Certificate)	Oct 2021
· Databases and <b>SQL</b> for Data Science with Python, <i>IBM</i> . (Certificate)	Sep 2021
· Machine Learning with python, IBM (Certificate)	July 2020
· Getting Started with <b>AWS</b> Machine Learning, AWS. (Certificate)	April 2020
· Machine Learning, Stanford University. (Certificate)	Oct 2019
· Introduction to the Internet of Things (IoT), Alison. (Certificate)	Oct 2019
· Introduction to <b>Data Science</b> , Alison. ( <u>Certificate</u> )	Oct 2019
• Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python, Udemy (Certificate)	July 2019

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- · Languages- Python, HTML, MATLAB, C++.
- · Frameworks- Django, Numpy, Flask, Tensor flow
- · Platforms- Git, AWS.
- · OS Linux, Windows

### **SPOKEN LANGUAGES**

- English (Full professional proficiency)
- · Hindi (Mother Tongue)
- French (Elementary proficiency)